# HEATHER DOLLAR

47 Hearthstone Circle, Bluffton, South Carolina 29910 (803) 586-9862 · hdollar@scsolicitor14.org

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Registered nurse with over 20 years of experience providing care to patients across the lifespan. Highly organized and enjoys multitasking to provide the best level of care possible. Experienced in a variety of settings including inpatient services and community-based care. Has a strong passion for evidence-based practice while incorporating trauma-informed, patient-centered care into all delivery of services. Has management experience and the ability to maintain all aspects of confidentiality. Has a firm understanding and knowledge base of infection control practices required in today's healthcare world.

### LICENSURE AND CERTIFICATION

#### **REGISTERED NURSE LICENSE**

South Carolina #213784, Expiration 04/30/2022

#### **AHA BASIC LIFE SUPPORT**

Certification, Renewal 11/2022

### SEXUAL ASSAULT NURSE EXAMINER - ADULT/ADOLESCENT

Certification, Renewal 12/2023

### SEXUAL ASSAULT NURSE EXAMINER - PEDIATRIC

Certification, Renewal 10/2022

### **EDUCATION**

#### MASTER OF SCIENCE IN NURSING

Walden University – Minneapolis, MN RN to MSN Track, have completed BSN content Current student

### **ASSOCIATE IN SCIENCE IN NURSING**

Excelsior College - Albany, NY Completion – 06/2011

#### **BACHELOR OF SCIENCE – BIOLOGICAL SCIENCES**

University Of South Carolina - Columbia, SC Completion — 05/2009

### **DIPLOMA OF NURSING IN LICENSED PRACTICAL NURSING**

Cotton Boll Technical Institute - Burdette, AR Completion – 08/2000

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### 01/2019 - PRESENT

### **REGISTERED NURSE, SANE PROGRAM COORDINATOR**

# 14TH CIRCUIT VICTIMS SERVICES CENTER SAFE PROGRAM – OKATIE, SC

Director and manager of community-based Sexual Assault Nurse Examiner Program founded in South Carolina's first Family Justice Center. Researched, wrote, and established all program policies and guidelines for program. Responsible for hiring, management, and education of up to 6-8 Registered Nurses. Collaborated with a multidisciplinary team within the community to ensure patients had highest delivery of patient-centered, trauma-informed care available. Participated in both community and state level committees, and active in educating addition groups within our community about the effects of violence on healthcare.

#### 08/2017 - 01/2019

# REGISTERED NURSE, EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT

## BEAUFORT MEMORIAL HOSPITAL – BEAUFORT, SC

Registered Nurse at a 197-bed hospital in North Beaufort County, South Carolina. Worked in an Emergency Department with 25-patient care beds and 16-patient fast track area. Assignments included triage nurse and patient assignments of up to 4-6 patients of varying medical emergencies including psychiatric, medical, and physical disorders. ACLS and PALS certification maintained during employment and active in educational opportunities when available. Functioned as a Sexual Assault Nurse Examiner when needed for patients presenting to the emergency department.

# 04/2017 - 08/2017

# REGISTERED NURSE, EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT

### LEXINGTON MEDICAL CENTER – LEXINGTON, SC

Worked in a 557-bed nonprofit hospital seeing over 350 patients daily in the emergency room. Responsible for a 3-4 patient assignment performing all aspects of emergency care to include medication administration, wound care, and patient teaching. Advance Stroke Life Support course completed and maintained during employment.

### 08/2014 - 04/2017

### **REGISTERED NURSE, EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT**

# **AIKEN REGIONAL MEDICAL CENTERS - AIKEN, SC**

Registered Nurse in a 273- bed hospital with a 35-bed emergency room servicing 120-150 patients daily. Served as the charge nurse, triage nurse, and primary nurse for the patient population seen. Active in establishing the surrounding 6-county's first Sexual Assault Nurse Examiner program based in the emergency room to service victims of violence of all ages. Took 24/7 call in additional to scheduled work hours. Participated in unit committees and recipient of nurse of the month during employment.

### 05/2012 - 08/2014

### REGISTERED NURSE, PEDIATRIC INTENSIVE CARE UNIT

## PALMETTO HEALTH CHILDREN'S HOSPITAL - COLUMBIA, SC

Registered nurse in a state of the art 18-bed Pediatric Intensive Care Unit and Pediatric Intermediate Intensive Care Unit providing care for more than 500 patients each year. Responsible for 2-3 patient assignment from newborn to young adult. Well versed in disease management, critical care

management of children, and medicine administration with children. Active participant in unit driven committees including taking role as wound care chair for Quality Improvement Initiative Committee.

# 09/2002 - 05/2012

# **REGISTERED NURSE, SURGICAL TRAUMA**

# PALMETTO HEALTH RICHLAND - COLUMBIA, SC

Worked in a 641-bed Level I Trauma Center serving more than 225,000 patients yearly. Responsible for a patient assignment from 4-6 patients as well as serving as the charge nurse of a group of up to 6-7 nurses. Well versed in IV medication administration, wound care, discharge planning, and patient-centered care to include family and patient education. Active in many unit committees including taking role as skin champion for unit. Primary preceptor for many new nurses and students, and Daisy aware nominee for extraordinary commitment to patient care.

### 03/2001 - 09/2002

# LICENSED PRACTICAL NURSE, CARDIOVASCULAR INTENSIVE CARE UNIT

### ST. BERNARDS MEDICAL CENTER - JONESBORO, AR

Worked in a 12-bed Cardiovascular Intensive Care Unit and cross floated to a 6-bed Coronary Care Unit. Responsible for up to 2 critically ill patients. Well versed in the management of patients post CABG, AAA repair and cardiac catherization. Responsible for vent management, critical care medications, and assessments.

### 09/2000 - 03/2001

# LICENSED PRACTICAL NURSE, TELEMETRY CARE UNIT

# ST. BERNARDS MEDICAL CENTER - JONESBORO, AR

Worked in a 440-bed Level III Trauma Center serving over 23 counties in Northeast Arkansas. Responsible for a patient assignment of 5-6 patients on a telemetry floor. Managed IV cardiac medications, patients following cardiac catherization procedures and versed in medication management.

### REFERENCES

Available Upon Request